Hello, welcome to class everybody. My name is David Brown. This is a grammar class. Hello. Welcome. Welcome to class. Norma. Welcome. Hello. Thank you. How are you? I'm doing good. How are you? I'm doing great. Thank you.
大家好，欢迎各位来到课堂。我叫戴维·布朗。这是一堂语法课。你好。欢迎。欢迎来到课堂。诺玛 (Nuòmǎ)，欢迎。你好。谢谢。你怎么样？我很好。你呢？我非常好。谢谢。
Norma, did you have a good weekend? Yes, I had* a good weekend with my family.
诺玛，你周末过得好吗？是的，我和家人度过了一个愉快的周末*。
Great. Excellent. Did you spend time with, you have a son, right? His name is Jose Pablo? Yes. He always tries* to play with me. So I can do anything at home about just playing with him.
太好了。非常棒。你和你儿子一起度过时光了吧，对吗？他叫何塞·巴勃罗 (Hésè Bābóluó)？是的。他总是想*和我玩。所以我在家除了和他玩，什么也做不了。
Okay, that does sound like a good weekend. In this lesson, Norma, we're going to talk about weekends and we'll talk about regular and irregular verbs, the difference between those two.
好的，听起来确实是个不错的周末。诺玛，在这节课上，我们将讨论周末，并且会讨论规则动词和不规则动词，以及这两者之间的区别。
And how to describe our weekends using pronunciation and also sequence adverbs. Let's read these objectives here. Can you see the screen, okay? Yes, I can see it.
以及如何运用发音和顺序副词来描述我们的周末。让我们读一下这里的学习目标。你能看清屏幕吗？是的，我能看清。
Okay, great. Let's start by reading this part right here. Can you read this line for me? Talk about the past. You see all past verbs like washed, went, ate.
好的，太好了。让我们从朗读这里开始。你能为我读一下这行吗？谈论过去。你会看到所有过去式动词，如 washed, went, ate。
to describe finished events. Okay. And the next one? And then the next order. Order your story. Use special words. First, then, next. After that, finally, to tell things in the right order.
用来描述已完成的事件。好的。下一个呢？然后是下一个顺序。组织你的故事。使用特定的词语。First, then, next. After that, finally，按正确的顺序讲述事情。
Sound clear, practice saying -ed verb endings correctly. Okay. And write your story. Write a short paragraph, three to five sentences about a personal past event.
发音清晰，练习正确发出 -ed 动词结尾的音。好的。然后写你的故事。写一个三到五句话的短段落，描述一个个人过去的事件。
Okay, great. So these are our goals for today's lesson.
好的，太好了。这些就是我们今天课程的目标。
We see that we have the past, the present, and the future. We have different conjugations and many students struggle with the past tense quite a bit for two reasons: One, there are different ways to pronounce verbs that end in ED.
我们知道有过去时、现在时和将来时。我们有不同的动词变位形式，许多学生在一般过去时态上遇到相当大的困难，原因有二：第一，以 ED 结尾的动词有不同的发音方式。
And also because there are so many irregular past tense verbs, probably more than 200 irregular past tense verbs that we need to memorize.
另外，因为有太多不规则的过去式动词，可能超过200个不规则过去式动词需要我们记忆。
So we see that the basic verb structure is basically verb plus ed. And that's the simple past. And that works most of the time. So we just add ed to the end of it. For example, we have finished and in the past, it is finished.
所以我们看到基本的动词结构基本上是动词原形加 ed。那就是一般过去时。而且大多数情况下都适用。所以我们只需在词尾加上 ed。例如，我们有 finish，在过去式中是 finished。
A base verb, and then the rest. Here's an example here. Can you read this example for me?
动词原形，然后是其余部分。这里有一个例子。你能为我读一下这个例子吗？
Present, watch TV, past, yesterday, I watched* a movie.
现在时，watch TV，过去式，yesterday, I watched* a movie.
Okay. Good. We're going to practice some pronunciation a little bit more. It could be difficult for native Spanish speakers to pronounce that ch sound in watched.
好的。很好。我们将多练习一些发音。对于母语是西班牙语的人来说，发出 watched 中 ch 的音可能有点困难。
But you'll get it. Don't worry.
但你会掌握的。别担心。
And so we see an example like this one, too. They play soccer. And then in the past becomes they played soccer. And you can hear a different pronunciation for this one.
所以我们也会看到像这样的例子。They play soccer. 然后过去式变成 They played soccer. 你可以听到这个词有不同的发音。
In the first one, a /t/ sound, the second one, a /d/ sound. And then here's another example. Can you read this one for me?
第一个是 /t/ 音，第二个是 /d/ 音。然后这里有另一个例子。你能为我读一下这个吗？
She cooks dinner past she chicken dinner last night.
She cooks dinner 过去式 she chicken dinner last night. (chicken -> cooked)
Great. So the basic spelling rules are that we need to add ed to the end of the verb.
很好。所以基本的拼写规则是我们需要在动词末尾加上 ed。
There are some times when we need to change the y to i and then add ed. For example, study becomes studied or cry,
有些时候我们需要把 y 改成 i 再加 ed。例如，study 在过去式中变成 studied，或者 cry，
becomes cried  with i ed.
在过去式中变成 cried，加上 ied。
But most of the time, you'll just add -ed to the end of the verb to make it past tense.
但大多数时候，你只需在动词末尾加上 -ed 就可以把它变成过去式。
All right. Let's continue. Do you have any questions for me before we continue on?
好的。我们继续。在我们继续之前，你有什么问题要问我吗？
No, I just want to, as you mentioned, it is difficult. This is one of the most difficult parts when I start learning English, the past tense because of that pronunciation part.
不，我只是想说，正如您提到的，这很难。这是我开始学习英语时最难的部分之一，就是过去时态，因为那个发音部分。
But we try practicing and practicing.
但我们努力练习再练习。
I understand. And it's normal to feel a little bit nervous when we try to do difficult things.
我理解。当我们尝试做困难的事情时，感到有点紧张是正常的。
So far, you're doing really, really good exceptional. So don't worry, Norma.
到目前为止，你做得真的非常非常好，非常出色。所以别担心，诺玛。
All right. So one challenging thing, as you mentioned, is knowing all of these are regular verbs.
好的。所以一个有挑战性的事情，正如你提到的，是了解所有这些规则动词。
And so we need to memorize them. There really is no way around memorizing these different verbs.
所以我们需要记住它们。记忆这些不同的动词确实没有捷径。
Of course, we need to use them in context, but we really need to memorize all of these irregular past tense verbs.
当然，我们需要在语境中使用它们，但我们真的需要记住所有这些不规则的过去式动词。
So we have some examples here. The past tense of go is went...the past tense of eat is ate.
我们这里有一些例子。go 在过去式中是 went... eat 在过去式中是 ate。
The past tense of have is had* the past tense of see is saw past tense of drink is drank past tense of make is made.
have 在过去式中是 had* see 在过去式中是 saw，drink 在过去式中是 drank，make 在过去式中是 made。
Good pronunciation. The past tense of buy is what? Bought.
发音很好。buy 的过去式是什么？Bought。
Oh, okay. And how about this one?
哦，好的。这个呢？
Past tense of wake up is woke up.
wake up 的过去式是 woke up。
All right. And then we need to remember these conjugations for the verb to be.
好的。然后我们需要记住动词 to be 的这些变位形式。
So not only do we have a regular one, sometimes they look totally different in past tense conjugations.
所以我们不仅有规则动词，有时它们在过去式变位中看起来完全不同。
So we have be and then was or were for the word to be.
所以我们有 be，然后是 was 或 were 作为 to be 的过去式。
All right. So these are just a small sample of irregular verb.
好的。这些只是一小部分不规则动词的例子。
I really recommend that when you have time, try to find lists of these irregular verbs and use them.
我真的建议你有时间的时候，试着找一些这些不规则动词的列表并使用它们。
Think about them whenever you speak about the past. Make sure that you're conjugating them correctly.
每当你谈论过去时，都要想到它们。确保你正确地进行了动词变位。
Let's test a couple of these. And I think we can continue on because you're doing really well.
让我们测试几个。我想我们可以继续了，因为你做得非常好。
The past tense of go is went the past tense of have is had the past tense of drink is drank.
go 在过去式中是 went，have 在过去式中是 had，drink 在过去式中是 drank。
Good. The past tense of buy is... Bought?
很好。buy 的过去式是…… Bought?
Wow. Okay. Your pronunciation really has improved a whole lot. I'm really impressed.
哇。好的。你的发音真的进步了很多。我印象非常深刻。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right. So we have three different ways that we pronounce these verbs that end in -ed.
好的。所以我们有三种不同的方式来发这些以 -ed 结尾的动词的音。
And we've had some implicit practice with this before, but I think it's really useful to understand some of these rules too.
我们以前也做过一些这方面的隐含练习，但我认为理解这些规则中的一些也非常有用。
We have three different sounds that we make whenever we pronounce verbs that end in -ed.
当我们发以 -ed 结尾的动词的音时，我们会发出三种不同的声音。
One is with a /t/sound here with your teeth.
一种是用你的牙齿发出的 /t/ 音。
The other one is with a /t/ sound and it's behind the teeth right there in the alveolar ridge, it's called.
另一种是 /t/ 音，它在牙齿后面，就在那个叫做齿龈缘 (chǐyínyuán) 的地方。
That's where we pronounce the d-d sound. And then we have the id sound.
我们在那里发 d-d 的音。然后我们有 id 的音。
So it starts with this vocal sound here is where vowels come from.
所以它从这个浊音开始，元音就是从这里来的。
And then it ends with the dip sound in the roof of your mouth.
然后它以你口腔顶部的 dip 音结束。
So we have dip and id and it depends on the final consonant.
所以我们有 dip 和 id，这取决于最后的辅音。
So the final consonant sound of watch, for example, is ch repeat repeat repeat.
所以例如 watch 的最后一个辅音是 ch，重复，重复，重复。
There you go. Very good. All right. So we have watched? This one's very difficult.
就是这样。非常好。好的。所以我们有 watched? 这个非常难。
Watched? Watched? Watched? Watched? Very good.
Watched? Watched? Watched? Watched? 非常好。
Great. And look becomes. Look.
很棒。然后 look 变成。Looked。
Looks very good. Stop is. Stop. Right. So we don't have a sound that starts here with the a /t/ at the end.
Looks 非常好。Stop 是。Stopped。对。所以我们没有以 a /t/ 结尾的音从这里开始。
And then we have the d sound. Remember in the roof of the mouth.
然后我们有 d 音。记住在口腔顶部。
So we have play in the past becomes remember /d/. Repeat after me.
所以我们有 play，过去式变成，记住 /d/。跟我读。
Very good. Played. Played.
非常好。Played. Played.
Good. This one? Opened.
很好。这个呢？Opened.
Great. And this one?
很棒。这个呢？
Lived. Wow. Perfect. Awesome.
Lived. 哇。完美。太棒了。
So you can memorize these rules here.
所以你可以记住这些规则。
You can learn them after some time of just practicing and hearing them for a long time.
经过一段时间的练习和长时间的聆听，你就能学会它们。
But if you remember that if it starts or rather if the final consonant is L B and B G M R Z or J,
但是如果你记住，如果它以 L, B, V, G, M, R, Z, 或 J 开头，或者更确切地说，如果最后一个辅音是这些，
then it will result in that /d/ sound at the end.
那么结尾就会发出那个 /d/ 音。
The most important rule to remember is that when the final consonant is "t" or "d",
需要记住的最重要的规则是，当最后一个辅音是 "t" 或 "d" 时，
then we're going to pronounce the -id at the end.
那么我们要在结尾发 -id 的音。
So we have wanted in the final consonant is "t".
所以我们有 wanted，最后一个辅音是 "t"。
wanted it's wanted the final consonant of need is what? Needed.
wanted，是 wanted。need 的最后一个辅音是什么？Needed。
So it's D. The final consonant is D. So it's needed and decided.
所以是 D。最后一个辅音是 D。所以是 needed 和 decided。
Decided. Perfect. All right. So we add an extra syllable with that id sound at the end.
Decided。完美。好的。所以我们在结尾加上了那个 id 音的额外音节。
I think we can continue on. How do you feel?
我想我们可以继续了。你感觉怎么样？
Does this seem easy to you or is it a little too difficult or what do you think?
这对你来说容易吗，还是有点太难了，或者你怎么看？
I think you're doing great.
我觉得你做得很好。
No, I feel comfortable.
不，我感觉很自在。